<TEI>
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title>
     Ghil'ad Zuckermann
    </title>
    <author>
     <orgName>
      Wikipedia contributors
     </orgName>
    </author>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>
     Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia (Wikimedia)
    </publisher>
   </publicationStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <bibl>
     <ptr target="https://co.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghil%27ad%20Zuckermann"/>
     <date>
      2018-08-16T17:09:07Z
     </date>
    </bibl>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body xml:lang="co">
   <head>
    Ghil'ad Zuckermann
   </head>
   <p>
    Ghil'ad Zuckermann (Tel Aviv, Israele, 1 di ghjugnu 1971) (D.Phil., Università di Oxford; Ph.D., Università di Cambridge) hè unu linguista talianu-australianu-israelianu-inglesu.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann hè prufessure di linguistica à l'Università di Adelaide, Australia.
   </p>
   <p>
    == Almae matres ==
   </p>
   <p>
    Collegio del Mondo Unito dell'Adriatico (Duino, Trieste, Friuli è Venezia Ghjulia, Italia)
   </p>
   <p>
    Università di Tel Aviv (Israele)
   </p>
   <p>
    St Hugh's College, Università di Oxford (Regnu Unitu)
   </p>
   <p>
    Churchill College, Università  di Cambridge (Regnu Unitu)
   </p>
   <p>
    == Opere ==
   </p>
   <p>
    === Libri ===
   </p>
   <p>
    Language Contact and Lexical Enrichment in Israeli Hebrew, 2003, Palgrave Macmillan (ISBN 9781403917232 / ISBN 9781403938695)
   </p>
   <p>
    Israelit Safa Yafa, 2008, Am Oved (ISBN 978-965-13-1963-1)
   </p>
   <p>
    Engaging – A Guide to Interacting Respectfully and Reciprocally with Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander People, and their Arts Practices and Intellectual Property, 2015
   </p>
   <p>
    Dictionary of the Barngarla Aboriginal Language of Eyre Peninsula, South Australia, 2017
   </p>
   <p>
    Jewish Language Contact (International Journal of the Sociology of Language 226), 2014
   </p>
   <p>
    Burning Issues in Afro-Asiatic Linguistics, 2012
   </p>
   <p>
    === Articuli ===
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad; Quer, Giovanni; Shakuto, Shiori (2014). Native Tongue Title: Proposed Compensation for the Loss of Aboriginal Languages, Australian Aboriginal Studies 2014/1: 55-71.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad; Walsh, Michael (2014). “Our Ancestors Are Happy!”: Revivalistics in the Service of Indigenous Wellbeing, Foundation for Endangered Languages XVIII: 113-119.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad; Walsh, Michael (2011). Stop, Revive, Survive: Lessons from the Hebrew Revival Applicable to the Reclamation, Maintenance and Empowerment of Aboriginal Languages and Cultures, Australian Journal of Linguistics 31: 111–127.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2009). Hybridity versus Revivability: Multiple Causation, Forms and Patterns, Journal of Language Contact 2: 40–67.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2006). A New Vision for "Israeli Hebrew": Theoretical and Practical Implications of Analysing Israel's Main Language as a Semi-Engineered Semito-European Hybrid Language, Journal of Modern Jewish Studies 5: 57–71.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2004). Cultural Hybridity: Multisourced Neologization in "Reinvented" Languages and in Languages with "Phono-Logographic" Script, Languages in Contrast 4: 281–318.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2003). Language Contact and Globalisation: The Camouflaged Influence of English on the World's Languages – with special attention to Israeli (sic) and Mandarin, Cambridge Review of International Affairs 16: 287–307.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2008). 'Realistic Prescriptivism': The Academy of the Hebrew Language, its Campaign of 'Good Grammar' and Lexpionage, and the Native Israeli Speakers, Israel Studies in Language and Society 1: 135–154.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2006). "Complement Clause Types in Israeli", Complementation: A Cross-Linguistic Typology, Oxford University Press, pp. 72–92.
   </p>
   <p>
    Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2006). " 'Etymythological Othering' and the Power of 'Lexical Engineering' in Judaism, Islam and Christianity. A Socio-Philo(sopho)logical Perspective", Explorations in the Sociology of Language and Religion, John Benjamins, pp. 237–258.
   </p>
   <p>
    Yadin, Azzan; Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2010). "Blorít: Pagans' Mohawk or Sabras' Forelock?: Ideological Secularization of Hebrew Terms in Socialist Zionist Israeli", The Sociology of Language and Religion: Change, Conflict and Accommodation, Palgrave Macmillan, pp. 84–125.
   </p>
   <p>
    Sapir, Yair; Zuckermann, Ghil'ad (2008). "Icelandic: Phonosemantic Matching", Globally Speaking: Motives for Adopting English Vocabulary in Other Languages, Multilingual Matters, pp. 19–43.
   </p>
   <p>
    == Filmografia ==
   </p>
   <p>
    Fry's Planet Word, Stephen Fry
   </p>
   <p>
    SBS: Living Black: S18 Ep9 - Linguicide
   </p>
   <p>
    Babbel: Why Revive A Dead Language? - Interview with Prof. Ghil'ad Zuckermann
   </p>
   <p>
    Language Revival: Securing the Future of Endangered Languages, edX MOOC
   </p>
   <p>
    == Liami ==
   </p>
   <p>
    "Lingua mosaica o lingua-Mosaico?: La genetica dell'israeliano" / Prof. Dr Dr Ghil'ad Zuckermann
   </p>
   <p>
    Ghil'ad Zuckermann, D.Phil. (Oxon.)
   </p>
   <p>
    University Staff Directory: Professor Ghil'ad Zuckermann
   </p>
   <p>
    Ghil'ad Zuckermann, Academia
   </p>
   <p>
    Jewish Language Research Website: Ghil'ad Zuckermann
   </p>
   <p>
    Professor Ghil'ad Zuckermann's website
   </p>
   <p>
    Australian of the Day: Ghil'ad Zuckermann
   </p>
   <p>
    Voices of the land, Anna Goldsworthy, The Monthly, September 2014.
   </p>
   <p>
    BBC World Service: Reawakening Language
   </p>
   <p>
    Selutis Alpinis (Se tu vens cà sù ta' cretis), Ghil'ad Zuckermann, "A site dedicated to the memory of Maestro Piero Poclen, a mentsh"
   </p>
   <p>
    == Da veda dinò ==
   </p>
   <p>
    Phono-semantic matching
   </p>
   <p>
    Lingua Barngarla
   </p>
   <p>
    == Rifarenzi ==
   </p>
   <p>
    Biugrafia
   </p>
   <p>
    Linguistica
   </p>
   <p>
    Scrivanu
   </p>
   <p>
    Australia
   </p>
   <p>
    Talianu
   </p>
   <p>
    Israele
   </p>
   <p>
    Università di Oxford
   </p>
   <p>
    Università di Cambridge
   </p>
   <p>
    Università di Adelaide
   </p>
   <p>
    Università di Queensland
   </p>
   <p>
    Università Nazionale di Singapura
   </p>
   <p>
    Università di Texas
   </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
